Well, a function is really boring if it
doesn't actually do anything. So, let's
make this function do something. So, I'm
going to say let my num one equal 10.
And I'll say let my num 2 equal 20. And
then I'm going to say um
let result equal my num one plus my num
two.
And now if we save that then we can call
this add two numbers function and then
we can alert result.
All right let's see what happens when we
do that.
So I'm going to bring this here.
I'm going to reload the page. Nothing's
happening. Why is that? So if I inspect
this page and I go to the console tab,
it said result is not defined. Weird
because result is defined right here.
Well, um in order to understand that, we
have to talk a little bit about scope.
So variables only live for a certain
amount of time. When you create
variables, um they take up space on your
computer. Um your computer only has so
much memory. um you'll have to look at
your computer to determine how much
memory it has, but your computer only
has so much memory. If you continue
filling that memory with variables,
eventually you will run out of space.
And you'll notice we never delete a
variable out of memory. So, if you
create a ton of variables, why isn't
your computer crashing when it runs out
of memory? Well, the answer to that
question um is the garbage collector. So
the garbage collector goes through and
it looks for variables that it knows
that you cannot access anymore. So when
you create a variable using let as the
keyword, it creates the variable within
the code block. So as long as it's
within these curly braces, you can
access that variable. As soon as it goes
outside of those curly braces, you can
no longer access that variable. So, as
long as I'm in here, I could alert
results. But as soon as I come out here,
I can't access results anymore because
the garbage collector came along and
looked at it and said, "Oh, you said I'm
only going to use result in these curly
braces." And so, as soon as you're out
of those curly braces, I'm going to go
ahead and delete result. So, it's going
through and automatically cleaning up
after you. Um, it's wonderful. Um, but
sometimes it can be frustrating when you
want to access a variable and it's stuck
somewhere else. Um, so if we want to
access that results variable that we
just created, then um, we need some way
of getting it out of this function and
back into our main program. Right now,
I've shown you how to do some work. So,
you can um, add numbers. Basically, the
doing work part just involves writing
code that you've already learned between
these curly braces. In the next video,
I'll show you how to access the result
of doing that work outside of those
curly braces and in your main